Philip J. Klass Collection 1948-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.59
American Philosophical Society
Klass has gone on to investigate numerous UFO sighting and abduction cases, including the 1975 Travis Walton "UFO Abduction" case, which he concluded was a hoax. Klass also investigated the MJ-12 Papers, which alleged that President Harry Truman created a top secret group called Majestic-12 to deal with the 1947 saucer crash. Klass' investigation demonstrated that the documents were counterfeit. In return Klass has been accused of being an agent of the U.S. government disseminating disinformation in a UFO cover-up, however, Klass doubts the ability of the government to cover up something as large as a crashed saucer in light of the failure to maintain secrecy around events such as Watergate and the Iran-Contra Affair. Admitting that if he obtained information that UFOs did exist he would not hesitate to write the article himself. Klass has the distinction of being labeled one of the leading UFO skeptics, along with Edward Uhler Condon and Donald Howard Menzel.
Out of his investigations, Klass has published seven books, his first being UFOs-Identified in 1968. He has also participated in UFO lectures and programs sponsored by both skeptics and pro-UFOlogists. In 1976 Klass was a founding member of the Committee for the Scientific Investigation of Claims of the Paranormal (CSICOP) along with Carl Sagan, Isaac Asimov, Paul Kurtz, Ray Hyman, James Randi, Martin Gardner, and Sidney Hook. The purpose of CSICOP is to support the analytical investigation of paranormal and fringe-science claims from a responsible, scientific point of view, and provide information to the general public.
Klass began donating his papers to the APS in 1988 with the view that the collection would one day help historians of pseudo-science understand how UFOlogy became so popular in the late-Twentieth Century. Philip Klass died on August 9, 2005 in Cocoa, FL.
Allen, Woody; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.; American Physical Society.; Association pour l'Investigation Historique des Phenomenes Insolites; Bartholomew, Robert E.; Canada. Canadian Army; Canada. National Research Council; Center for UFO Studies; Committee for the Scientific Investigation of Claims of the Paranormal; Condon, Edward Uhler, 1902-1974; Cronkite, Walter, 1916 -; Eastern Airlines; Esterle, Alain; Friend, Robert J.; Fry, Daniel W.; Gill, William B.; Goldwater, Barry; Graham, Lee M.; Haines, Richard F.; Harder, James A.; Hopkins, Bud; Howe, Linda; Hynek, J. Allen, (Joseph Allen), 1910-1986; Jacobs, David M. (Michael), 1942 -; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961; Klass, Philip J.; Kral, Elmer; Littmann, Mark; Maccabee, Bruce S.; Mack, John E., 1929-; McDonald, James E., 1920 -; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Menzel, Donald Howard, 1901-1976; National Investigations Committee on Aerial Phenomena.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization; Oberg, James E., 1944 -; Patuxent Naval Air Test Center (Md.); Royal Canadian Mounted Police; Sagan, Carl, 1934-1996; Salisbury, Frank B.; Schroth, David A.; Sheaffer, Robert; Smithsonian Institution.; Society for the Investigation of the Unexplained; Sprinkle, R. Leo, 1930 -; Stacy, Dennis; Steiger, Brad; Strieber, Whitley; Taves, Ernest H. (Ernest Henry), 1916-; United Airlines; United Nations. Atomic Energy Commission.; United States Air Force--Operation Blue Book; United States Air Force; United States. Army; United States. Central Intelligence Agency; United States. Coast Guard; United States. Congress; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; United States. House of Representatives; United States. Navy.; United States. Office of Naval Intelligence; University of Colorado-UFO Study; University of Michigan; Vallee, Jacques; Aerial Phenomena Research Organization, Inc.; Aeronautics and Astronautics; Air and Space Magazine; Airships; Alien abduction; Apollo 12 (Spacecraft); Apollo 8 (Spacecraft); Audiotapes; Ballistic missiles; Balloons.; Close Encounters of the Third Kind; Combustion, Spontaneous human; Condon Report; Crop circles; Denver UFO Society; Department of Scientific and Industrial Research; Directed energy weapons; Discovering science; Fate magazine; Focus magazine; Fund for UFO Research, Inc.; Gemini Project (U.S.); GEPAN (Unidentified Aerospace Phenomena Study Group)-French Space Agency; Helicopters; Hill Abduction Case, 1961; Hypnosis; Journal of Abnormal Psychology; Journal of Scientific Exploration; Life magazine; MARINER 4 (Spacecraft); Miscellaneous; MUFON; Mysteries old and new; National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); National Enquirer; New York Review of Books; New York Times; New Yorker; Newspaper clippings; Optical illusions; Parade Magazine; Photographic analysis; Photographs; Photomethods; Playboy; Project Apollo (U.S.); Project Blue Book (U.S.); Psychiatry; RADAR; RB-47 UFO Case, July 1957; Read; Satellites; Saucer smear; Scholastic Book Services; Second Look; Skeptical Inquirer; Soviet Union; Space based weapons; Strategic Defense Initiative; Strategy for Peace Conference; Unidentified flying objects; Unidentified flying objects in motion pictures; Unidentified flying objects in popular culture; Unidentified flying objects--Religious aspects; Unidentified flying objects--Sightings and encounters; Venus (Planet); Videotapes; Washington Post; World Almanac Book of the Strange; Zond IV (Spacecraft)
- Series I. Correspondence, 1966-1992; 2 lin. feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains incoming and outgoing correspondence, the latter in the form of either carboncopies or photocopies. The series is arranged alphabetically, and then chronologically within each folder, and comprised of folders originally labeled by Klass as miscellaneous. For particularly extensive or relevant correspondence, we have provided individual folders. Among the several folders labeled as "Miscellaneous Correspondence" are materials that relate either to Klass's publications or to other UFO topic. Correspondence related to UFO cases investigated by Klass is located in Series II.
  - Aerial Phenomena Research Organization, Inc., 1967-1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Albrecht, Herbert O., 1968-1975 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allan, Christopher, 1982-1984 (Box Series I-1)
  - Andrus, Walter (MUFON), 1981-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Astronomy Magazine, 1975 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bengtson, Goran, 1977-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bissonnette, William E., 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Blackwell, James L., 1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Blann, Tommy R., 1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - Boger, Robert F., 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bowker, Robert F., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Boykin, Joyce, 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Campbell, Stuart, 1978-1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Cerney, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Clark, Phillip S., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Condon, Edward Uhler, 1968-1971 (Box Series I-1)
  - Covez, M. L., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Crystall, Ellen B., 1982-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Cunniff, Owen, 1975-1981 (Box Series I-1)
  - Dewan, Edmond M., 1967-1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Discovering Science, 1975 (Box Series I-1)
  - Earley, George W., 1968-1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Easley, Robert S., 1968-1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Eichorn-von Wurmb, H.K., 1968-1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Eramia, Bob, 1986-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Fate Magazine-UFO Article, 1975-1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Fenwick, Lawrence J., 1978-1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Fitzgerlad, Randy ("Second Look"), 1978-1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Flodin, Bertol, 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Frank, Helen, 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Garate, Frances, 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Gardyan, Edward J., 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Girard, Robert C., 1985-1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - Goldsmith, Donald, 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Gotlib, David A., 1991 (Box Series I-1)
  - Graham, Lee M., 1979-1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Greenfield, Allen H., 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Grossman, Wendy M., 1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Heighton, David, 1979-1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Keith, Noel L., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Klass, Philip J.-Form Letters, 1969-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Klass, Phillip J.-"The Fly in the Saucer" Parade Magazine, 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Korff, Kal K., 1976-1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Kret, Virgil-"UFO Psychic", 1986-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Kurtz, Paul, 1978, 1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Laporte, Wayne, 1979-1980 (Box Series I-2)
  - Larson, Kenneth Lloyd, 1968 (Box Series I-2)
  - Lemming, James R., 1987 (Box Series I-2)
  - Levin, Norman, 1967 (Box Series I-2)
  - Levitt, I.M. (Franklin Institute), 1967 (Box Series I-2)
  - Lind, Tom, 1978-1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Littmann, Mark, 1975-1978 (Box Series I-2)
  - Low, Robert, 1966-1973 (Box Series I-2)
  - Luce, Thomas A., 1977 (Box Series I-2)
  - Lynch, Niel [no folder in Box] (Box Series I-2)
  - Magnusson, Sven, 1975-1984 (Box Series I-2)
  - Mathes, Joe (UFO Photo-hoax), 1975-1982 (Box Series I-2)
  - Mayer, Harry F., 1978 (Box Series I-2)
  - McQuail, Owen, 1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Menzel, Donald H., 1970, 1973 (Box Series I-2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) A-C (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) D-F (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) G-I (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) J-L (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) M-O (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) P-R (Box Series I-2)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) S-U (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: publications) V-Z (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) A-C (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) D-F (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) G-I (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) J-L (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) M-O (Box Series I-3)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) P-R (Box Series I-4)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) S-U (Box Series I-4)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) V-X (Box Series I-4)
    - Misc. Corresp. (re: UFO Sightings and Theory) Y-Z, unidentified (Box Series I-4)
  - Morris, Scot, 1984 (Box Series I-4)
  - Moseley, Jim (ed. Saucer Smear), 1987-1992 (Box Series I-4)
  - Narasimhan, D., 1979 (Box Series I-4)
  - National Geographic Society, 1981-1982 (Box Series I-4)
  - Pelletier, Bruce, 1991 (Box Series I-4)
  - Phenomena Research (Gribble, Robert J.), 1978-1979 (Box Series I-4)
  - Pinvidic, Thierry, 1979-1983 (Box Series I-4)
  - Pittock, A. Barrie, 1979-1980 (Box Series I-4)
  - Quensel, Victor G., 1985 (Box Series I-4)
  - Read, 1969-1977 (Box Series I-4)
  - Retoff, William, 1977, 1980 (Box Series I-4)
  - Ridpath, Ian, 1978, 1987 (Box Series I-4)
  - Sachs, Margaret, 1978 (Box Series I-4)
  - Sagan, Carl, 1981-1988 (Box Series I-4)
  - Saunders, David R., 1973 (Box Series I-4)
  - Schiller, Robert, 1975-1976 (Box Series I-4)
  - Schmitt, Donald R., 1980-1981 (Box Series I-4)
  - Shelton, Jay, 1984-1989 (Box Series I-4)
  - Sherman, Harold, 1975 (Box Series I-4)
  - Shneour, Elie A., 1978 (Box Series I-4)
  - Smith, Richard, 1969 (Box Series I-4)
  - Stacy, Dennis, 1991 (Box Series I-4)
  - Strauch, Arthur A., 1967 (Box Series I-4)
  - Stybenski, Leonard L., 1970 (Box Series I-4)
  - Tiedt, Dennis Carl, 1980-1981 (Box Series I-4)
  - Tikey, Joseph W., 1981 (Box Series I-4)
  - Tosellie, Paolo, 1980-1981 (Box Series I-4)
  - Tough, Allen, 1987 (Box Series I-4)
  - Unidentified Flying Object Report and Information Center, 1978 (Box Series I-4)
  - Van Kampen, Hans, 1986-1987 (Box Series I-4)
  - Wanderer, Robert, 1981-1987 (Box Series I-4)
  - Webbe, Stephen, 1978 (Box Series I-4)
  - Winkler, Jerome T., 1968 (Box Series I-4)
  - Wirstrom, Charles (Box Series I-4)
- Series II. UFO Case Files, 1948-1993; 5.5 lin. feet
  Series II is comprised of "case files" relating to UFO investigations that were either undertaken by Klass, or that were otherwise of interest. Case files include correspondence, newspaper clippings, government reports, and photographs. Among the most noteworthy material in this series is Klass's extensive correspondence with Bruce Maccabee -- a physicist employed by the Naval Surface Warfare Center and a leading pro-UFOlogist. Klass considered their investigation of the 1978 New Zealand UFO Case (as his most challenging and time consuming investigation. The basis of this investigation is that a TV camera crew flying off the coast of New Zealand filmed a giant glowing ball. Klass eventually determined the object to be the lights from a Japanese squid boat filmed through an improperly installed telephoto lens. In addition to their letters, maps, photographs, nomograns and charts were used to facilitate an understanding of the case's technical aspects.
  - Alabama: Cindy Vodovoz Abductin Case, 1973, 1993 (Box Series II-1)
  - Alabama: Montgomery-Chiles-Whitted Case, 1948, 1975 (Box Series II-1)
  - Arizona: Phoenix-Christy Dennis "Confessed Abductee", 1970, 1978-1983 (Box Series II-1)
  - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975, 1975-1980 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Allen Dalis), 1976 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (APRO/Lorenzens), 1975-1977 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Backster Affair), 1976-1980 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Mike Rogers), 1975-1980 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Misc. Interviews), 1975-1979 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (newspaper clippings), 1975-1977 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Original Polygraph), 1975-1978 (Box Series II-1)
    - Arizona: Sitgreaves National Forest-Travis Walton Case, 1975 (Travis/Duane), 1975-1978 (Box Series II-1)
  - California: Big Sur-UFO Case, 1964, 1982-1993 (Box Series II-2)
  - California: Catalina Island-UFO Movie, 1974, 1974-1979 (Box Series II-2)
  - California: Minuteman-Launch Generated UFO Report, 1976, 1977 (Box Series II-2)
  - California: Ridgecrest-UFO Case (Jupiter), 1986, 1990 (Box Series II-2)
  - California: Santa Ana-Heflin UFO Photo Case, 1965, 1965-1978 (Box Series II-2)
  - Colorado: Aguilar-"Ghost of Aguilar" Plasma-UFO Case, 1949, 1968-1969 (Box Series II-2)
  - Connecticut: Columbia-BSM's Xmas-Lights UFO Case File, 1981, 1985 (Box Series II-2)
  - D.C.: Washington-CIA Psychic UFO Case, 1959, 1976-1978 (Box Series II-2)
  - D.C.: Washington-RADAR UFO Cases / RADAR Angels, 1951-1988 (Box Series II-2)
  - Florida: Gulf Breeze-6 AWOL Soldiers, 1990 (Box Series II-2)
  - Florida: Jacksonville-Huge Triangle UFO Case / Pilot Report, 1967, 1984 (Box Series II-2)
  - Florida: Ocala-Navy RADAR UFO Case, 1978, 1978-1979 (Box Series II-2)
  - Florida: West Palm Beach-RADA-Visual UFO Case, 1972, 1968-1972 (Box Series II-2)
  - Georgia: Griffin (see Texas: Grapevine-UFO "Trace Cases") (Box Series II-2)
  - Georgia: Leary-Jimmy Carter's UFO/ Venus sighting, 1969, 1976-1978 (Box Series II-2)
  - Illinois: Lake Zurich-UFO Case, 1969 (Box Series II-2)
  - Indiana: Anderson-CBFOS "Non-hoax-hoax" photo case, 1981, 1982 (Box Series II-2)
  - Iowa: Fireball "UFO" Case, 1969, 1969-1974 (Box Series II-2)
  - Iowa: Maynard-UFO-Hoax Experiment, 1971 (Box Series II-2)
  - Kansas: Delphos-UFO Case, 1971-1981 (Box Series II-3)
    - Kansas: Delphos-UFO Case Corresp. File, 1971, 1971-1973 (Box Series II-3)
    - Kansas: Delphos-UFO Case General File, 1971, 1971-1981 (Box Series II-3)
    - Kansas: Delphos-UFO Case General File, 1971 (photographs) (Box Series II-3)
  - Kentucky: Goodman Field (Ft. Knox)-Mantell UFO Case, 1948 (Box Series II-3)
  - Louisiana: Minden (see Texas: Grapevine-UFO "Trace Cases") (Box Series II-3)
  - Maryland: Cheverly-Case (Bruce MacCabee), 1975 (Box Series II-3)
  - Michael Bershad (aka Steve Kilurn) Abduction Case-see Alabama: Cindy Vodovoz Abductin Case, 1973 (Box Series II-3)
  - Michigan: Monroe County-UFO Case, April 1967, 1967-1968 (Box Series II-3)
  - Minnesota: Warren-Deputy Sheriff "UFO-Collision," 1979, 1979-1982 (Box Series II-3)
  - Mississippi: Pascagoula-"Abduction" Case, 1973, 1973-1976 (Box Series II-3)
  - Missouri: Columbia-UFO Case, 1973, 1974-1975 (Box Series II-4)
  - Missouri: Piedmont-UFO Case, 1973 (Box Series II-4)
  - Missouri: St. Louis-Advertising Airplane "UFOs," 1977, 1979 (Box Series II-4)
  - Montana: Great Falls-UFO Case, 1950, 1968-1974 (Box Series II-4)
  - Nebraska: Omaha-William Rogers Plasma-UFO/Fireball, 1968, 1968-1969 (Box Series II-4)
  - New Hampshire: Newton-UFO Case, 1967, 1968 (Box Series II-4)
  - New Hampshire: The Hill Abductin Case-John Quinn, 1978-1979 (Box Series II-4)
  - New Jersey: North Bergen-Stonehenge Apartments, 1975, 1975-1977 (Box Series II-4)
  - New Jersey: Wanacque-Resevoir Case File, 1966, 1966-1968 (Box Series II-4)
  - New Mexico (see Texas: Grapevine-UFO "Trace Cases") (Box Series II-4)
  - New York: Albany-Radar-Visual UFO Case, 1974, 1974-1976 (Box Series II-4)
  - New York: Griffiths, AFB-F-94c Crash "UFO" Case, 1954, n.d. (Box Series II-4)
  - New York: Homer-UFO Case, 1964 (not investigated by PJK) (Box Series II-4)
  - New York: Schenectady-UFO Case, 1967, 1968-1970 (Box Series II-4)
  - North Carolina: Fayetteville-"Capt. Bauer" UFO Case (hoax), 1972, 1977 (Box Series II-4)
  - North Carolina: Linville Falls-Brown Mountain Lights, 1968, 1968-1977 (Box Series II-4)
  - North Carolina: Rural Hall-UFO Case, 1967, 1968 (Box Series II-4)
  - North Carolina: Wake Forest-Jay Berner Hoax UFO Report, 1980, 1992 (Box Series II-4)
  - Ohio: Dayton-UFO Movie, John Getter, 1973, 1973-1980 (Box Series II-5)
  - Ohio: Ravenna Case, 1966, 1967-1976 (Box Series II-5)
  - Oklahoma: McAlester-Ray Fowler's (Alledged) DC-8 UFO Incident, 1973, 1975-1979 (Box Series II-5)
  - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950, 1950-1983 (Box Series II-5)
    - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950 (BSM-PJK Corresp), 1976-1983 (Box Series II-5)
    - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950 (BSM / Mrs. Trent), 1974-1977 (Box Series II-5)
    - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950 (BSM 1975 Analysis) (Box Series II-5)
    - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950 (BSM 1981 Report), 1981-1982 (Box Series II-5)
    - Oregon: McMinnville-UFO Case, 1950 (JEM and Misc.), 1950-1976 (Box Series II-5)
  - Pennsylvania: Beaver-UFO Case Lucci Photos, 1965, 1967-1977 (Box Series II-5)
  - Pennsylvania: West Mifflin-"UFO Surgery" Case / Frank Dorsey, 1980, 1983-1984 (Box Series II-5)
  - Pennsylvania: Carbondale-UFO (Hoax) Case, 1974 (Box Series II-5)
  - Pennyslvania: Pittsburgh-Leonard Demchak Plasma -UFO Hoax, 1972, 1972-1973 (Box Series II-5)
  - Texas: Dayton-Cash-Landrum "Radiation Burns" Case, 1981, 1981-1983 (Box Series II-5)
  - Texas: Dayton-Cash-Landrum "Radiation Burns" Case, 1981 (newspaper clippings), 1981-1983 (Box Series II-5)
  - Texas: Grapevine-UFO "Trace" Cases (Tommy Blann), 1985 (Box Series II-5)
  - Texas: San Antonio-UFO Case, 1973, 1973-1975 (Box Series II-5)
  - Texas: Surfside-Plasma-UFO Case, 1966, 1968 (Box Series II-5)
  - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975, 1975-1979 (Box Series II-5)
    - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975, 1978 (Box Series II-5)
    - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975 (Grand Forks AFB) (Box Series II-5)
    - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975 (Loring AFB), 1975-1979 (Box Series II-5)
    - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975 (Malstrom AFB) (Box Series II-5)
    - United States Air Force: Air Base Incidents, 1975 (Wurtsmith AFB) (Box Series II-5)
  - United States Air Force: Project Blue Book File-1968 March 3 Incident (#1), 1968-1986 (Box Series II-6)
  - United States Air Force: Project Blue Book File-1968 March 3 Incident (#2), 1968-1986 (Box Series II-6)
  - United States Air Force: RB-47 Case, 1957 (CUFOS Challenge), 1977 (Box Series II-6)
  - United States Air Force: RB-47 Case, 1957 (Klass, Philip K.-"The RB-47 UFO Case-A New Explanation"), 1971 (Box Series II-6)
  - United States Air Force: RB-47 Case, 1957 (PJK Investigated), 1969-1975 (Box Series II-6)
  - United States: Great East Coast UFO, 1986, 1987 (Box Series II-6)
  - Utah: Sandy-Hoax UFO Photo case, 1978 (Box Series II-6)
  - Virginia: Ft. Belvoir-Stofko Case, 1957, 1967 (Box Series II-6)
  - Virginia: South Hill-UFO Case, 1967, 1967-1972 (Box Series II-6)
  - Virginia: Wytheville-UFO sightings, 1987-88 (Mini-Flap) (Box Series II-6)
  - West Virginia: Parkersburg-Derenberger UFO Case, 1966 (Box Series II-6)
  - Argentina: UFO Case-Oberg Explanation, 1980, 1980-1984 (Box Series II-7)
  - Australia: NullarBoxr-Car UFO Incident, 1988 (Box Series II-7)
  - Canada: Calgary-UFO-Pix Case, 1967, 1970 (Box Series II-7)
  - Canada: Falkonbridge, Ont.-UFO Case, 1975, 1976-1977 (Box Series II-7)
  - Canada: Gander, Newfoundland-Navy Aircraft UFO Case, 1951, 1951-1980 (Box Series II-7)
  - Canada: Langenburg, Sas.-UFO Case, 1974, 1974-1982 (Box Series II-7)
  - Canada: Vancouver Island, B. C. -Frisbee-like UFO, 1981, 1986-1989 (Box Series II-7)
  - France-GEPAN UFO Investigation, 1977-1985 (Box Series II-7)
  - Guatemala: Guatemala City-UFO video-tape, 1977, 1978 (Box Series II-7)
  - New Guinea: Boxiana "UFO-occupant" case, 1959, 1973-1978 (Box Series II-7)
  - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978, 1978-1987 (Box Series II-7)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. #1, Dec. 1980-Aug. 1981 (Box Series II-7)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. #2, Sept. 1981-Mar. 1982 (Box Series II-7)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. #3, Apr. 1982-July 1983 (Box Series II-8)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. #4, Nov. 1983-Sept. 1986 (Box Series II-8)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. Film Case #1, 1980 Jan.-June (Box Series II-8)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. Film Case #2, 1980 July -Aug. (Box Series II-8)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Corresp. Film Case #3, 1980 Sept.-Dec. (Box Series II-8)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Green NIB #1, 1986 Apr.-May (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM Green NIB #2, 1986 June-Sept. (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-BSM's anti squid Boat arguments, 1982-1986 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-DSIR / William, 1979-1981 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-MacCabee, Bruce "Analysis and Discussion of the Images of a Cluster of Periodically Flashing Lights off the Coast of New Zealand", 1987 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-MacCabee, Bruce "What Really Happened in New Zealand", 1979-1981 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-Maps, 1980 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-Misc., 1979-1981 (Box Series II-9)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-Newspaper, 1978-1979 (Box Series II-10)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-Periodic Flashing Lights, 1984-1987 (Box Series II-10)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-PJK Nomograms, 1981 (Box Series II-10)
    - New Zealand: UFO Case, 1978-Right Angel Issue-90 vs 125 deg, 1981-1986 (Box Series II-10)
  - Philippines: Re-entry UFO, 1979 (Box Series II-11)
  - United Kingdom: Lakenheath-AIAA UFO Case, 1956, 1970-1976 (Box Series II-11)
  - United Kingdom: Lakenheath-Gordon Thayer, 1956, 1954-1981 (Box Series II-11)
  - Other, 1962-1977 (Box Series II-11)
    - Other: Apollo/Gemini UFO Report Claims, 1975-1976 (Box Series II-11)
    - Other: MARINER-4 Incident: Concocted Hoax, 1965, 1974-1975 (Box Series II-11)